荣誉出品
分享创作之乐，共赏字幕之美
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：@幻游虚云路
校对：@幻游虚云路
众生之灵皆恒久
All men's souls are immortal
唯正义之魂，神圣而恒久 - 苏格拉底
but the souls of the righteous are immortal and divine. - Socrates.
亥伯龙！
Hyperion!
我的先知…你梦里看到了什么？
My oracle ... what vision did you dream?
泰坦们…被释放了
The Titans... unleashed
谁放的？
By whom?
国王亥伯龙
King Hyperion.
他在寻找伊庇鲁斯之弓以主宰世界
He seeks the Bow of Epirus to rule over mankind.
我们必须祈祷
We must pray.
当这个世界还年轻
When this world was still young
早在人类和野兽出现在这个世界之前
long before man or beast roamed these lands,
惊天战神
Immortals
天堂爆发了一场战争
There was a war in the Heavens.
神灵都曾以为拥有不死之身
Immortals, once thought incapable of death,
直到他们发现能互相残杀
discovered they had the power to kill one another.
在这场战争中丢失了
Lost in this war,
一件非凡的神器：
was a weapon of unimaginable power:
伊庇鲁斯之弓
The Epirus Bow.
胜利者们宣称他们自己为诸神
The victors declared themselves Gods.
而那些战败者被贬为泰坦
While the vanquished were renamed Titans
永远囚禁在地狱山深处
and forever imprisoned within the bowels of Mount Tartarus.
亿万年过去了，人类繁荣昌盛…
Eons passed,Mankind flourished...
而诸神之战渐渐湮没在岁月的洪流中
..And the great war receeded from memory.
而曾经邪魔…
But the evil that once was...
再度出现
...has reemerged.
亥伯龙军团来了
Hyperion is here.
他冲我来的
He comes for me.
我们必须走了
We must go now.
赛伯琳圣殿，希腊，公元前1228年
SYBELLINE MONASTERY GREECE, 1228 BC.
站住！你不能进入这里，这里是神圣之地！
Stop! You cannot enter here. This is sacred ground!
对谁神圣？
Sacred for whom?
你们想干嘛？
What do you want with us?
圣女先知在哪里？
Where is the virgin Oracle?
污蔑圣地，必遭天谴
Defile this house further and you will risk the wrath of the gods.
神？
The Gods...
Gods ...
神？？
你召唤他们前来啊
Go ahead, call upon them.
祷告啊
Pray...
请求他们的帮助
Ask for their help...
向那些袖手旁观，形同虚设的神祈祷
Pray to the same Gods who idly stood by
当我们的妻子和孩子
as my wife and my children
在遭受疾病肆虐的时候…
were stricken by disease..
我呕心沥血祈求上天的保佑
I too have cried to the Heavens for help.
结果不但没有得到怜悯
But instead of mercy,
他们还冷眼旁观
I was met with silence
让我家人遭受莫大的苦痛
and the retched sight of my family suffering like animals...
直至死去…我他妈永不再信这种伪神
...until their deaths. Your gods will no longer mock me!
我将释放泰坦
I will release the Titans.
现在停止这种疯狂为时未晚
It's not too late to end this madness.
如果祈祷，还可以被救赎
Salvation can be yours,if you wish it.
让我帮你浴火重生吧，神父
Let me enlighten you, Priest.
我将会结束神界的统治
I will end the reign of Gods.
科珀斯海湾半岛
Kolpos Peninsula
好好挥舞那斧头，忒修斯
You wield that axe well, Theseus.
说不定哪天，挥斧子挥的帅气还能找到个老婆！
Maybe some day, we'll see you use that same determination to find a wife.
是不是你和我妈已经串通好了？
Are you conspiring with my mother now?
你妈担心你娶不到嘛
She worries about you.
我才不需要你们操心
There is no need to worry about me.
作为一个战士
You know being a warrior
不单是指你能以剑退敌
is not just being able to strike your opponent down with a sword.
更应该明白出剑有因
It's finding  good reason to draw your sword in the first place.
出剑只为保护吾爱之人
I draw my sword to protect those that I love.
那其他人呢
And what about others?
其他人都是敌人咯
They turned their backs on me.
那些手无寸铁，手无缚鸡之力的弱者？
The weak, the defenseless?
谁来保护他们？
Whose going to protect them?
行了吧，你杞人忧天会衰老的很快的
Be careful, too much worry will make you an old man.
贱货
Whore!
为圣庭点最后一盏灯
Last lights for the Holy Labyrinth!
让先祖安息
Let the ancestors rest in peace.
忒修斯…
Theseus ...
又一次意外么？
Another accident?
忒修斯，也许哪天你陪我一起去祈祷
Theseus, maybe one day you will join me in prayer.
求神在我老去之前赐予我多点子孙
Ask the Gods to grant me grandchildren before I'm too old.
妈，神话都是哄小孩的，我可不信那些
Mother, the gods are children stories, My spear is not.
妈，你知道
You know, mother,
造人可比点点蜡烛复杂多了
It takes more than lighting candles to make babies.
而且那些个神父的帽子也太搞笑了
Besides the priest wears a ridiculous hat.
- 母亲，留在这儿　- 忒修斯…
- Mother, stay here. - Theseus ...
村民们
Fellow Helariks
你们一定想知道我们为什么来这
It is with great concern that I stand before you.
赫拉克里恩之王亥伯龙已经占领了赛伯琳圣殿
The Heraklion king,Hyperion,has seized the Sybelline monastery.
他现在离这里也就一天的路
He is only a day's march from here.
你们必须立即离开这里
We must to evacuate this village immediately!
安静点，大家
Quiet, please!
士兵们！我们留下也是死路一条！
soldiers! We stand no chance!
死路一条！
We stand no chance!
他因为太紧张有些慌乱了，别误会
He is delirious from battle.Please!
我们劝所有大人小孩带上你们的行李
We ask every man, woman and childgather your belongings
往地狱山方向撤退
and leave for Mount Tartarus.
找到巨墙后的难民营，你们就会得到保护
Seek refuge behind the safety of the Great Wall. There, you will be protected.
那些需要更多时间的
Anyone that needs more time,
老弱病残，我们会多保护你们一天
the old, the infirm, will be escorted in a days' time.
准备撤离！
Get ready for departure!
你站错了队伍
You're with the wrong party.
不是要我们撤退到地狱山么？
Is this not the caravan traveling to Tartarus?
是的，但你不能和我们一起走
It is.But you will not be traveling among us.
早上和你的同类们一起租
Go in the morning with your own kind.
什么我的同类
My kind?
奴隶和异类明天才出发
Peasants & undesirables travel tomorrow.
我的血和你是一样的
My kind's blood is the same color as yours.
忒修斯，请…
Theseus, please ...
妈
Mother.
这里干嘛？
What is happening here?
一个杂种和他的娼妓母亲
A bastard and a whore mother
住手！
Stop!
退下！
Fall back!
- 放下剑　- 我不放
- Put the sword down! - I will not!
- 杀了他　- 再动他就死
- Kill him! - Try and he dies first!
你在做什么，兄弟？
What is it that you want, brother?
看起来我的同类要明天上午才能走
It seems as though my kind travel in the morning.
但我也想他们得到应有的保护
I want them to have a proper escort.
再动一下，我就把刀插到你头上
Move again, and I will bury this in your skull!
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
忒修斯
Theseus.
我们没时间在这应付内乱，忒修斯，放开他
Now is not the time for violence Theseus. Let him go.
除非你承诺会保护我们所有人
Only if I have your word the rest of the village will be protected.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我会留下几个明天能保护你们的人
I will leave capable men for the caravan tomorrow.
- 杀了这叛徒　- 你他妈的还想怎样！
- Kill this traitor! - I will not have a spectacle!
把他给我绑了，别在这里碍老子的眼！
Restrain him! Get him outta my sight!
把他带走
Take him away.
留着你的体力，忒修斯，还需要你对付赫拉克里恩大军呢
Save your blood lust for Heraklion veins, Theseus.
加入我们军团吧，看你有两下子，哪学的？
Join our ranks.You have been trained well.
我有一个好老师
I had a good teacher.
你来当我的左右手，我们一起对付亥伯龙军团
I could use a man of your skill at my side to defeat Hyperion's legions.
我为什么要帮你？
Why would I serve you?
你们这么瞧不起我们
You would have so easily abandoned us...
妈，我们走
Let's go, Mother.
雷山德，你不再是我军团成员
Lysander, you are no longer part of this army.
一会把你的武器盾牌都给我上缴了
Relinquish your shield and your spear
待在这儿明天和他们一起走
and remain here to travel with the peasants tomorrow.
- 你都看见了…　- 就这样
- But you saw him... - It is done.
回头见
See you later.
你的行李呢，前辈？
Where are your things, old man?
你准备好撤退没有？
Are you not prepared for the march?
战争是给你们肌肉男和野心家的游戏
Such odysses were meant for the young people and expectant.
不适合像我这样的老人
Not for a worn out old goat like me.
请你再考虑清楚
Please reconsider.
留在这里等于自杀
You know staying here is suicide.
如果赫拉克里恩人来了，兴许我还能死的爽快点
If the Heraklians show up at least I'll be spared a slow death.
至少我知道，他们下手可不会犹豫不决的
From what I understand, indecision is not their style
你真疯狂！
You are mad.
只是太累了
Just tired.
活着并不是最重要的事情，忒修斯
It's not living as such that's important Theseus.
而是活的有尊严
It's living rightly.
我从没见过像打仗那样勇猛凶残的
They fight with a ferocity unlike anything I've seen.
他们眼睛都能看透黑夜似的
Almost as if they could see in the darkness.
要多彪悍有多彪悍
It's always suited them.
说的他们跟神一样
You speak as if they are not human.
他们是人
There are human.
他们也是赫拉克里恩人，和我们一样
They're Heraklians, they bleed just as we do.
唯一的区别是他们为信仰而战
The only difference is they fight for a belief
因此他们下手异常凶狠
which allows them to kill without restraint.
所以他们总是能赢
That is why they will win.
雷山德，我记得头儿说要你交出武器的
Lysander, I thought the Sun ordered to surrender your weapons.
他是说过
He did.
现身
Reveal yourself.
给我现身
- 父亲？　- 雅典娜！
- Father... - Athena...
- 宙斯　- 免礼
- Zeus... - No need for formalities.
没有其他神注意到咱们吧？
None of the other gods are looking?
是吧？
Are they?
怎么？
What?
刚刚你的样子
When you walked through here just now,
真像个慈祥的父亲
you actually looked like a father...
或者说更像一个祖父
...or maybe a grandfather.
我们在这里必须小心
We must tread carefully here
已经触犯天条了
heed the law
不能让凡人看见我们的神化之身
None of the mortals on earth should witness us in our immortal form.
但父亲，你已经身处险境了
But father, you've come dangerously close.
你在这教导忒修斯已经多年了
You have been influencing the boy Theseus for years.
我是扮成普通人的
It is one of them
不是以神的身份，就像他的一个朋友
never as a god.Only as his friend.
为什么选他？
Why him?
他不畏艰险
He does not fear danger.
无视伤痛，不惧失败
No pain, defeat
一往无前
or ridicule.
他唯一担心的是
He fears only the failure to
不能保护他所爱的人
defend that which he holds so dear.
至亲之人
His loved ones.
如果说有谁能带领他们对抗亥伯龙
If there is one human  who can lead them against Hyperion
只能是忒修斯
It would be Theseus.
但得靠他自己来抉择
But it must be his choice.
他是叛变的，他要见国王
He defected. He wants to meet the king
快走
Move!
你是那边来的逃兵
You are a defector from what I understand.
- 陛下，是的　- 我不是你的国王
- Yes, my king. - I am not your king.
我希望你是
I wish you to be.
但你其实是个叛徒，不是吗？
But you are a traitor by definition,are you not?
我的军团要叛徒来干嘛？
What would I want with a traitor? In my midst.
我可以告诉你哪个村庄没有布防
I can you tell of a village, that lies unprotected,
哪里你能找到年轻的女子
where you can gather young women...
我已经有很多了
I have plenty of women.
- 找到奴隶和武器　- 我也有很多武器
- Slaves and weaponry... - I have plenty of weapons.
我想要的伊庇鲁斯之弓
What I want is the Epirus Bow.
就像这个地方
Like this monastery
你们崇拜的这个圣殿
I have moved every precious stone
我翻遍了的每一个角落
you people have worshipped upon...
但仍然无法找到它
and I have yet to find it.
你有见过赛伯琳祭司么，叛徒？
Have you ever met a Sybelline monk, traitor?
这些祭司们盲目效忠于圣女先知
The monks of his order are unwavering in their obedience to the virgin oracle.
只要手法到位，先知就能告诉我们那个弓在哪里
With the right prodding, the Oracle can see where the bow rests.
她能找到是吧，祭司？
Couldn't she, Monk?
告诉她在那
Tell me where she is.
我知道你们的信条，祭司
I know your faith, Monk.
赛伯琳祭司任何情况下都是不能杀人的
Sybellines are forbidden to take a life under any circumstance.
包括自杀
Even their own.
除了告诉我我想知道的，你别无选择
You have no choice but to tell me what I want to know.
你有没有舌头我都要你说出真相
A monk can be made to talk with or without his tongue.
把他交给牛头怪，逼他说出先知在哪
Give him to the beast Make him tell you where the oracle is being kept.
你有孩子吗？
Do you have any children?
目前还没有
Not yet.
一个男人的精子是他最强大的武器
A man's seed can be his most brutal weapon.
你们的后代都将在他们的孩子的眼睛里…
For generations, your people will stare into the eyes of their sons
看到我的影子
and they will see my likeness.
我会被刻画进每一个眼神
I will be remembered in every glance,
每一个微笑…
In every smile ...
每一滴眼泪…
In every tear ...
直至永恒
... For an eternity.
但在你跨进这里之前，我明白
But before your baptism,you should Understand
你来这里不是因为想加入我们
that you are not drawn here to my flame... on instinct.
而是因为你就是一个叛徒
... Because you are a traitor.
你来这里，因为你就是个懦夫
You're here because you are a coward.
而且我们的世界并不需要…
And our world does not need ...
懦夫
anymore cowards.
所以我得帮这个世界一个大忙
So I shall do this world a great favor.
给你做个耻辱标记
And mark you as one of us.
再剥夺你繁衍后代的权利
And rid you of the ability to populate the earth.
叛徒
Traitor!
可能你听不见
Although you will not hear them
你的祖先们正在他们的坟墓里抽泣
Your forefathers weep in their graves.
因为他们的血脉
For the future of their bloodline
今晚起彻底后继无人
Ends with you tonight.
前辈
Old man?
前辈？
喂
Hello?
忒修斯，你的愤怒正在控制你
Your anger moves you Theseus.
你该学会如果控制它
You must learn to master your emotions.
注意节奏，忒修斯
Rhythm, Theseus,
节奏
rhythm
不！
Noooooooooo!
等待！
Wait!
死神在此
Witness hell!
不！
No!
把他送监，他能在盐矿干活
Give him to the jailer.He can work in the salt mines.
他的痛苦才刚刚开始
His pain has just begun
亥伯龙军团手段极其残忍
Hyperion's legions show no mercy
他们摧毁所有他们路过的每个圣殿
They have destroyed every holy shrine
只为找到伊庇鲁斯之弓
in their quest for the Epirus Bow.
他们找到它只是时间的问题
It is only a matter of time before they find it.
我注意到这个暴君对孕妇特别关照
I've noticed their king takes the greatest care with women that carry a child.
只为之后亲手杀死她们
And personally sees to their slaughter.
这简直是对希腊人种族屠杀
He ventures to eradicate the Hellenic future.
他们根本没有交战原则
They honor no rules of engagement.
所以常胜
Effective!
现在看来是
At least, thus far.
常胜
Effective?
是懦弱
Cowardly.
都有可能，但希腊人还没找到对付的办法
That may be,But the Hellenics have yet to adapt.
- 直到他们真正勇敢起来　- 宙斯你为什么不干预一下？
- And until they do... - Isn't it time to intervene,Zeus?
你怎么能看到这样的屠杀，但还袖手旁观？
How can you stomach bearing witness such atrocities whilst doing nothing?
这是天条
Obey the Law.
神不能直接干预人界的事情
No God shall interfere in the affairs of man.
除非泰坦被释放了
Unless the titans are released
如果我们期望人类相信我们…
If we are to expect mankind to have faith in us...
那我们就应该对他们有信心
then we must have faith in them.
他们有自由意志的权利
We must allow them to use their own free-will.
那如果他们找到伊庇鲁斯的弓呢？
And what if they unearth the Bow?
如果你们中任何一个出手帮助他们
If any of you come to the aid man
或者以神的力量影响人类的事情
or otherwise influence the affairs of mankind as a God,
那惩罚就是死
the punishment will be death.
她们是谁？
Who are they?
圣女先知
The Virgin Oracles
赫拉克里恩人可能已发现先知了
The Heraklians must have found the temple.
- 你不认识她们？　- 不认识
- You don't know of them? - I don't.
不过我不介意用一晚深入了解一下她们
but I wouldn't mind knowing them all for a night.
你是一个小偷？
You are a thief?
是的，女士
I am a thief my lady.
如果不是这些锁链，我就把你的心偷走
Were it not for these chains,I would steal your heart.
今晚我们必须逃出去
Tonight, we must flee this place.
找几个能打的人
Whichever is strong enough to fight
- 那边那个男的　- 他都没喝水
- And that man there. - He didn't even go for the water.
他活不到明早
He won't make it to morning.
随时准备好
Just be ready.
离他远点
Stay apart!
去里面
Go inside ...
要活着
Stay alive.
先知
My Oracle...
你说你看到未来的画面
You were presented with vision.
你看到了什么？
What have you seen?
水边的奴隶
Slave by the water.
得到神灵的指引
He is touched by the Gods
如果他投靠了亥伯龙
If he embraces Hyperion
整个希腊就万劫不复
all of Greece will be destroyed.
叫警卫来
Summon the guards.
她们中只有一个是真的先知
Only one of them is the true Oracle.
据说她的圣洁无可替代
They say that she is pure...
其余人都是来保护她的
The others are there to protect her identity.
圣女先知有预知未来的天赋
The virgin Oracle is blessed with visions of the future.
如果谁亵渎了她的身体，她的天赋就没了
- If she were to be violated? - The prophecy would be corrupted.
真可惜
What a waste...
- 站住　- 钥匙
- Halt! - Keys!
去吧，我的先知，我们搞定警卫
Go, my Priestess. We'll take care of guards. Run!
快走
Get out!
你最好睡个觉
You should get some sleep
其实我没那么脆弱
You know I am stronger than I look.
我没事
I'll be fine.
也许…
Perhaps
你难以入睡，可能是…
you have trouble sleeping Because…
因为那些幻像吓到你
you are haunted by your visions.
你还会读心术
A warrior who reads minds...
有些人认为我的天赋是神赐
Some people do consider my visions to be a gift.
神赐？这算哪门子神赐？
A gift?How can they be considered a gift?
你能看到未来
You can see the future,
但又没有办法改变未来
But you do not have the power to change it
对不起
Sorry
你为什么这么做呢？
Why would you do such a thing?
就为个无名小卒铤而走险
You risked your life to save a complete stranger.
我想你应该没有信仰吧
Only faithless man would ask such a question.
我的母亲是个非常虔诚的信徒
My mother was woman of faith.
即使她信仰的神往往对她视而不见
And her Gods were absent when she needed them the most.
所以，我不信这些
As was I...
所以我们就只能悲哀？
So we both mourn?
你对过去耿耿于怀，而我对将来忧心忡忡
You, for what has past,and I, what is to come.
这是怎么回事？
What happened to them?
我下令谁都不许动她们
I gave an order for them not to be touched.
她们试图逃跑,我的国王
They tried to flee, my king.
我们有七个好手都被他们杀了
Seven of our best men were killed in the struggle.
七个好手被几个女人杀了？
Seven of your best men,killed by women?
我只想知道伊庇鲁斯之弓在哪
I wish to know where the Epirus Bow rest.
你们谁能告诉我吗？
Which of you can tell me this?
谁是真的先知？
Which of you is the true Oracle?
别逼我动用非常手段
If I am forced to search you out by other means,
你们会感觉生不如死
you will experience disomfort.
作为女性所不能忍受的侮辱
Discomfort unique to your gender.
所以，告诉我…
So you tell me
谁是真的？
which one of you is her.
我就是你要找的
I am the one you seek.
不，是我
No, it is I.
我才是你要找的
I am the one you seek.
另外那个也这么说
The other one said the same thing
都说自己是先知
They all claim to be the Oracle.
另外的那个？
-The other one?
是的，我的国王
Yes, my king.
其他那个？哪一个？
The other one? What other one?
她们有四个人
There were four of them.
有一个跑掉了
One of them escaped...
和一帮水井边的奴隶一起
..With a group of slaves from the watering hole.
- 蒙特刚　- 在
- Mantragkona! - Sire.
把跑掉的那个找回来
Find the one that escaped.
我要活的
Bring her to me alive!
黑海
The Dark seas..
这些水里尽是石油
These waters are thick with oil.
那条什么船
and the boat?
赫拉克里恩的普通商船
It's a Heraklian merchant ship.
我们最好能把那船抢了，然后去南面
Our best bet is to ambush it and head south.
- 南面不是我们的目的地　- 对我来说是
- South is not our journey. - Well it is for me.
据我所知
From what I hear ...
那边的妇女很容易丰衣足食
the women down there can get to the meat of a Malakian chestnut
只要会点口活
... Only with their tongues.
要不咱们试试你行不行，亲爱的？
Shall you and I test the limits of that desire, my dear?
神给了我预知的能力
The gods have given me vision.
而你只顾一己私欲
Yet all you do is dream of your appetites
我只管我是否满足
I would rather follow my appetites,
懒得理会你们是否欲求不满
than to follow hallucinations of a harlot.
- 她可是高级祭司　- 关我什么事
- She's a high priestess - It doesn't matter to me
高阶祭司或妓女，我反正要去南面
A priestess or whore, I'm heading south.
我说什么招惹你了？
Was it something I said?
那么，我的朋友，你想怎样？
Well friend? What will it be?
跟我去南边
South with me,
或者你跟着…
Or will you follow...
这位女士吗？
the lady?
都不是
Neither.
我会乘船向北
I'm taking that ship north
去被亥伯龙军团占领的圣殿
to Hyperion's camp at the monastery.
你的想法让我觉得你已经疯了，“殿下”
Your saviour sounds a lot like a mad man to me, Your highness.
不过呢
Personally
我宁愿和疯子一边，而不是和他对着干
I would rather fight with a madman, than against him.
你看到了吗？
Are you minding this?
这个就是宙斯常说的有为青年，是不是？
That is the mortal your father so extolls,is it not?
现在和先知在一起了
And he is with the Oracle.
波塞冬，如果宙斯起疑心，我们会帮你圆场的
Poseidon, if Zeus were to suspect you, we will come to your defense.
掌舵！
At the helm!
你不是说这就是艘商船！
I thought you said this was a merchant ship!
我想我说错了！
I guess I was wrong!
海面似乎也太平静了点…
The sea has forever been an unpredictable domain...
晴天霹雳的时候
When the cloudless skies thunders, stand fast!
最好是躲起来
... Better to leave.
- 现在就跳船！　- 稳住！
- We have to jump now! - Stand fast!
你知道那浪不是冲我们来的
You knew that wave would save us.
我只看到在滔天巨浪
What I see is only a glimmer
冲着我们扑面而来
of what may come to pass.
是你的行动拯救了大家
Your actions & desires shape what lies ahead.
你还看到什么了？
What else have you seen?
一个身体裹着床单，躺在石头上
A body wrapped in a shroud, on a rock.
你拿着伊庇鲁斯之弓
You holding the Epirus Bow and...
而且，你归顺了亥伯龙
embracing Hyperion.
不可能！
Impossible!
我永远不会归顺于他
I would not embrace Hyperion!
他杀害了我的母亲
He killed my mother.
你母亲？
Your mother?
你看见她被埋葬了吗？
Was she given a proper burial?
没有
No.
她仍然在她被杀害的地方
No. She still lies where Hyperion cut her down.
那你必须亲手埋葬她，这是她的信仰
Then you must bury your mother.Her faith demands it
我才不信仰那些神
I do not believe in the gods.
但她信仰
But she believed.
她虔诚的信仰，忒修斯
She believed, Theseus.
你必须回到你们村
You must return to your village.
找到先知没有？
Have you found the Oracle?
找到了，但是守卫在我们赶到之前被杀光了
We did my lord, But our men were lost before we could recover her.
一场风暴要了他们的命
A storm swept them to sea.
先知呢？
And the Oracle?
她活下来没有？
Did she survive?
她正前往科珀斯海湾，和几个奴隶一起
She travels towards Kolpos with the slaves.
她可能是带他们去找神弓
She could be leading them to the Bow.
让牛头怪到科珀斯海湾那边去
Send the beast to Kolpos.
我们现在出发去地狱山
We will go to Tartarus.
- 蒙特刚？　- 主人
- Montragkonie? - sire
你留守圣殿
You stay here.
在矿坑里设好埋伏
Set an ambush in the pit
对不起，我没有保护好你，妈妈
I'm sorry I couldn't protect you mother.
但我向你保证我会好好活下去
But I promise you our family name will not die with me.
亥伯龙的军团正在地狱山集结
Hyperion's legions are gathering at Tartarus.
那将决定是否希腊命运就此终结
That is where Hellenes will fall.
未来还没有定论
That future is not set
但可以肯定
But likely.
会有一场血腥的屠杀
It will be a slaughter.
你也没有信仰
You have no faith.
异类
Heathens!
你说的对，达里奥
That is true, Darius.
但不是没有过
But not always.
小时候，我祈求神灵
When I was just a boy,I prayed to the gods
给我一匹马
for a horse
但神没给我回应
The gods never answered me,
所以我自个偷了一匹
so I stole one instead.
我们被敌人包围了
We are surrounded by atheists.
没事了…没事了，忒修斯
It's alright... It's alright, Theseus.
我怎么了？
What happened to me?
你的手
Your arm.
伤口上有毒
You were poisoned
其他人在哪？
Where are the others?
他们在安葬达里奥
They're putting Darius body to rest.
她是对的
She was right.
我多年来所怀疑的
For all those years, I doubted it.
怀疑他们…是否存在
I doubted…their existence.
你的母亲不虚此生，忒修斯
Your mother's death was not in vain, Theseus.
上天注定你的命运
It was fate that brought you back...
和神弓一起
for the Bow.
拿着它，忒修斯
With that in your hands Theseus,
就能带给希腊人胜利
it will bring Hellenus victory.
你是对的，忒修斯
You were right, Theseus.
我的天赋就是我的诅咒
My visions are a curse.
我想用我自己的眼睛重新审视这个世界
I want to see the world through my own eyes
用我的心灵去感知
and feel with my own heart
用我的身体去感受
and to touch with my own flesh.
祭司，看我昨晚搞到什么东西
Hey monk!I did some "shopping" last night.
很犀利，啊？
Good weapon, huh?
很高兴看到你们都活着
Good to see you're still alive.
- 我还担心那毒会要你的命　- 的确就差一点
- I was worried that cow got the best of you. - He almost did.
是她救了我
She saved my life
好像不止救了你命这么简单
Looks like she did more than that.
我说…
Careful...
你是得到了神弓
Just because you have that bow
并不代表我们都得听你的
doesn't mean I'm gonna treat you any differently.
好吧
Good.
我们现在就去圣殿
We march to the monastery.
还得拼上一命
We have a war to fight.
地狱山
Mount Tartarus
那些信徒相信泰坦
The faithful believe the Titans are
仍被关押在大山深处
still buried deep within the mountains.
巨墙是希腊人抵抗你的唯一屏障
The Great Wall is the Hellenecs only hope against your army.
屏障？
Defences?
其实，这里以前是个水坝
Originally, there was a dam,
后来希腊人把它进行了改造
but the Hellenecs have since adapted it.
但他们没料到将要面对的是你的军队
No one could have anticipated the enemy you have become.
有多少？
How many are there?
这里有多少人我真不清楚，陛下
How many have made it here, Your Majesty. I'm not sure.
- 有多少？　- 我真不知道，陛下
- How many? - I'm not sure, Your Majesty.
- 800人　- 城门呢？
- 800. - And the gate?
20英尺的大理石，重超过12吨
20 feet of marble stone, weighing over 12 tons.
设计时就考虑到要坚不可摧，陛下
It was designed to be impenetrable, your majesty.
你难道不知不管什么城门
Have you known of a gate
其实都非固若金汤，嗯…？
designed to be anything but?
去找点乐子
Go be of service somewhere else.
他们人在哪里？
Where is he?!
亥伯龙的军团不是驻扎在这的？
I thought Hyperion was suppose to be camped here.
我们必须继续赶路
We should continue.
过了桥到地狱山还有2天的路程
Tartarus is another two days along this ridge.
这是什么声音？
What is that sound?
不！
No!
我的姐妹们！
My sisters!
她们在里面！
They're in the bull!
不！
No!
我的姐妹们！
My sisters!
- 我是先知　- 我是你们要找的
- I am the Oracle! - I'm also looking for.
忒修斯，他们还有人在这
Theseus! They are still here.
到达地狱山前别停下来
Do not stop until you reach Tartarus.
这马会一直狂奔直到断气为止
The horses will run until their hearts give out.
亥伯龙就要拿到神弓了，赶紧走！
Hyperion will soon have the Bow.Leave!
原谅我，父亲！原谅我吧！
Forgive me, father! Forgive me!
我只是为了凡人犯了点错
I only broke the law to protect the mortal
我不会允许任何神来帮助你
No God will ever again come to your aid!
从现在开始你就待这！
You are on your own!
你明白我的意思么，凡人？
Do you understand, mortal?
我对你有信心，忒修斯
I have faith in you, Theseus.
证明给我看
Prove me right!
领导你的人民
Led your people.
我终于得到我小时候祈求的马了
The horse I prayed for when I was a boy.
这马怎么回事？
What is wrong with them?
它们要死了
They're dying.
驻守圣殿那边的人在哪里？
Where are my men?
还没有回来
They have yet to return, sire.
老鹰有没有带回什么信？
What does the sign on the bird tell you?
说
Speak.
神灵…
The gods ...
从天而降
They came from above.
- 神灵？　- 陛下，那些神把我们的人全杀了
- The gods? -They appeared and laid waste to the men, my king.
神灵
The gods.
和先知一起的几个奴隶都得到他们的庇护
They protected the slave who travels with the Oracle.
神灵和他们并肩作战
The Gods fight on their behalf, sire.
如果传出去了，我们会阵脚大乱
If the men hear of this,there will be panic
我知道，我知道
I know, I know.
和平年代，黑发人送白发人
In peace,sons bury their fathers.
战争年代，白发人送黑发人
In war,fathers bury their sons.
我们正处于战争中吗，父亲？
Are we at war, father?
我们有重要信息要向议会报告
I have important information for the Council.
忒修斯？
Theseus?
我知道他，让他通过
I know this man.Let him through.
我希望你是来和我们并肩作战的
I hope you've come to join the fight.
军队在哪里？
Where is the army?
给我说说那个奴隶
Tell me about the slave.
是不是你们村的？
He's from your village, is he not?
他回答我！
Answer me!
是
Yes.
他是一个异族
He was a peasant.
我也是
As I was myself.
- 对不起，陛下，我不是想…　- 闭嘴
- Forgive me, Your Majesty. I meant no... - Quiet.
什么家庭？
The family?
他的母亲被奴隶强奸过
His mother was raped by some villagers.
谁都不愿意娶她
Nobody would marry her.
所以他是一个私生子
He was a bastard.
他什么名？
And his name?
忒修斯
Theseus.
好极了，我与他见一面
Very well. I wil meet him.
赫里奥说他有重要情况向我们汇报
Helios tells me that you have information useful to us.
亥伯龙已经拿到伊庇鲁斯之弓
Hyperion is in possession of the Epirus Bow.
伊庇鲁斯之弓
The Epirus Bow?
是的，大力神赫拉克勒斯打造的
-Yes, the weapon forged by Hercules.
我小时候听说过同样的故事
I heard the same stories you did as a child.
神住在天上，而泰坦埋在岩石里
Gods in living in the clouds and Titans buried in rocks..
听我说，我开始也不相信
Listen! I was a disbeliever just like you are.
但是，伊庇鲁斯之弓是真的
But the Epirus Bow exists.
我知道有很多希腊人…
I understand that there are many Hellenecs...
信仰神话和神灵
who put great faith in the myths and the gods
但我们作为希腊议会不会相信这个
but we in the Hellenac Council do not.
神灵都是象征性的，仅此而已
They are metaphors son,nothing more.
我们是法治社会讲求的是谈判和依据
We are a society of  laws based on negotiation and reason.
如果你试图通过和亥伯龙谈判
If you try to negotiate with Hyperion,
你会害死我们大家
you will be the death os us all.
难道你要我们接受
If I were to accept your council,
一个科珀斯海湾来的无名小卒的建议？会有用？
Theseus from Kolpos, what would it be?
封锁大门，准备战斗
Seal the gates and prepare for war!
我们正等着外面的部队返回
We have Happolyt battalions returning,
不会有部队回来了
No one will return!
最后只有我们几个了
We are the last!
你会理解为什么我不接受
I'm sure you'll understand if I do not accept the advice
一个魅惑的通灵者和她的异类情人的建议
of an alluring palm reader and her peasant lover.
长官，赫拉克里恩派使者来了
Sir, a Heraklian envoy approaches.
看见没有？
There, you see?
谁都不愿意卷入战争
No ruler wishes for war.
什么建议都不如坐下来想想怎么谈判
They only wish to be taken seriously at the bargaining table.
通知议会成员准备谈判
Alert the Council and prepare a delegation.
准备！
Bows!
停下！
Stop!
停下，再不停下我们就放箭了
Stop, Remain still,or we will be forced to fire upon you!
把手举起来
extend your arms outward!
他拿着橄榄枝表示和平
He bears the olive branch of peace.
我们国王想找
My king wishes to speak
一个来自科珀斯海湾的叫忒修斯的谈谈
with the one called Theseus from Kolpos.
忒修斯！
Theseus!
亥伯龙的使者想和你谈谈
Hyperion's envoy desires a word with you.
就像我曾预见的，他会张开双臂欢迎你
Like the vision.He sends for you with arms open.
想让你归顺于他
Seeking an embrace of loyalty
淮德拉…
Phaedra...
万一你是错的呢？
Have you never been wrong?
跨出大门，我们就保护不了你了
We can't protect you beyond this gate.
我是忒修斯！
I am Theseus!
走过来，我有个消息给你
Come closer, I have a message for you.
不要冒这个险
Do not risk it.
最多，也就少个奴隶而已
At worst, you lose a peasant.
这里？
Better?
可以
Yes.
为什么蒙着脸？
Why do you cover your face?
我只是信使
All are equal in Hyperion's midst.
带上个面具，完成任务了事，不想惹麻烦
I myself am only a vessel for of his demands, nothing more.
他提我的名字干什么？
And he ask me by name?
- 他是知道　- 他怎么知道的？
- Indeed he does. - And how does he know it?
忒修斯，没什么是国王不知道的
Theseus, there is little the king does not know.
他知道你没有父亲
He knows that you have no father
其实他也一样，从小遭人排挤
and like him,you were cast aside by your very own people.
他可了解我的愤怒？
Does he know of my rage?
他知不知道我会用我的剑放干他的血？
Does he know that I live only to see his blood on the end of my sword?
他知不知道他亲手杀了我母亲？
Does he know that he butchered my mother?
现在他看到了你的脸，所以他知道了
Now that, he's seen your face, he knows
你没那么大本事
You wouldn't make it.
懦夫！
coward!
跟我走吧，忒修斯
Embrace me, Theseus.
他们不会采纳你的建议的
They will never give you a say at their table.
但我会让你成为我的左膀右臂
But you could sit at the head of mine.
这场战争只是个开头
Long after this war is over
将来普天之下都会是我的领土
My mark will be left on this world forever.
我的帝国将永盛不落
The sun will never set on my blood, Theseus.
这就是我给你的优厚条件
This is what I offer.
这就是恒久
immortality
丰功伟绩可以
Deeds are eternal, not the flesh.
但轮不到你
... Not the flesh.
现在你有神灵保佑
The Gods may be on your side
但明天…我就放出泰坦
but tomorrow.....I unleash the Titans.
你们讨论什么？
What was discussed?
封锁城门
Seal the gate.
- 他什么条件？　- 封锁城门
- What were his demands? - Seal the gate.
忒修斯…
Theseus ...
- 是亥伯龙吗？　- 我差点要他命
- That was him, wasn't it? - I was that close!
我不知道我能否办到宙斯要求我做的
I don't know if I can do what Zeus asks me.
如果你有疑虑，说明真相已经近了，忒修斯
By doubting, one comes to truth, Theseus.
神灵不会看走眼
The gods chose well.
长官，前面有动静了
Sir! There is movement on the front.
去看看
Go and look.
他拿的什么？
What is he holding?
弓
A Bow!
打开门！
Open the gate!
这一切的背后！
Behind it all!
回头！
Turn back!
大家听我说！
Listen to me!
听
Listen
你是谁，凭什么告诉我们应该怎么做呢？
Who are you to tell us what to do?
我的确是个小人物，但我是好人，我叫忒修斯！
I am nobody to tell you what to do! I am Theseus, a good man.
和你们一样，一腔热血，但同样畏惧！
One of you,I share your blood and I share your fear!
如果我们现在逃跑
But to run now
等于把我们的灵魂，以及我们的孩子的灵魂
we offer our souls and the souls of our children
置于无尽的深渊
to a terrible darkness.
拿起武器，我们必须战斗！
Hold! We must stand and fight!
一夫当关万夫莫开！
Their numbers count for nothing in the tunnel!
各就各位！
Stand your ground!
你根本不必担心
You do not have to fear anything.
别以为他们蒙个脸，有几条伤疤
Just because they have scold their faces and scarred their bodies,
就证明他们比我们勇敢
does not mean they are braver or stronger than we are.
比我们更强壮
or stronger than we are.
他们是懦夫…
They are cowards ...
只敢藏在面具背后！
They hide behind their masks!
和我们一样都是血肉之躯
There are human and they bleed like you and I.
坚守阵地
Stand your ground!
为荣誉拼了！
Fight for honor!
为了战友拼了！
Fight for the man beside you
为家人拼了！
fight for those who bore you!
为孩子拼了！
For your children!
为未来拼了！
For your future!
为家族拼了！
Fight for your name! Survive!
拼死只为
Fight..
流芳百世！
For immortality!
今天，用敌人的鲜血书写历史！
Let us write history with Heraklian blood! our history!
国王亥伯龙
King Hyperion ...
我们可以协商
... We can negotiate.
跟你没什么好谈的……
I see no reason to ...
忒修斯！
Theseus!
我在这儿
here I am!
海湾的杂种！
Theseus of Kolpos!
- 你的国王呢？　- 我没有国王
- Where is your king? - He is not king!
忒修斯！
Theseus!
我在你身后
I'm behind you.
淮德拉
Phaedra!
淮德拉？
Phaedra?
留在这儿
Stay in the shrine!
亥伯龙！
Hyperion!
不！
No!
忒修斯？
Theseus?
我拿到弓了！
I got the Bow!
斯塔沃
Stavros.
我拿到弓了！
I got the Bow!
我尽量拖住他们，你赶紧跑！
I'll hold them while I can!Get out of here, now!
谁不怕死就来？
Which one of you comes for me huh?
你们谁都别想离开这儿
None of you will not leave this place.
快走！
Leave here!
这已经不再是你的战斗！
This is no longer your fight!
去找亥伯龙！
Find the Hyperion.
和你的神一起上路
Die with your gods.
雅典娜！
Athena!
父亲…
Father ...
不要就此放弃
Do not forsake my kind
不知道这是种什么感觉
What does it feel like knowing...
知道自己永不会被世人记起
..knowing that there will be no memory of you?
我会记得
I've won.
我的死会让我成为传奇
My death, will make me a legend.
我的事迹
And my deeds...
会永载史册…
..Will go down in history!
我来告诉你故事该怎么写
I'm writing your history.
做到这一点！
Do it!
这就是你的最后呼吸，亥伯龙
This is your last embrace, Hyperion.
看着我
Look at me.
看着我！
Look at me!
我就是你的
I'm the last thing ...
最终宿命
... You see.
是什么…
What is ...
不
No. ...
众生之灵皆恒久
All men's souls are immortal,
唯正义之魂，神圣而恒久
But the souls of the righteous are immortal and divine.
曾今有位义士，忒修斯
Once an faithless man,Theseus
为拯救人们舍身取义
.gave his life to save mankind
由此得以登天化神
and earned a place amongst the gods.
他的勇敢换来上天的恩赐：
They rewarded his bravery with a gift:
一个儿子
a son
阿卡马斯
Akamas
不要对你的幻觉产生恐惧，小朋友
Don't be afraid of your visions, little one.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
阿卡马斯
Akamas.
Akamas?
如雷贯耳
Strong name.
我认识你的父亲
I knew your father.
他是个勇敢的人
He was a very brave man.
不久的将来，就是你的时代了
Soon..It will be your time.
我的什么时代？
My time for what?
对抗无尽的邪恶，阿卡马斯
The fight against evil never ends, Acamas.
天庭将重燃战火
War is coming to the Heavens.
你父亲也会在那
And your father will be there.
为你的未来战斗
Fighting for your future.
阿卡马斯
Akamas?
阿卡马斯！
Akamas!
他是谁，儿子？
Who is he, my son?
是一位…
just a ...
一位老人
just a oldman